so this is some questions on the shorter
note on an inkjet
so in the second paragraph gives us
suited quotes just doing the basic
characteristics of a determined thing
which are I'll read the English
translation the rising is manifest
disappearance is manifest change while
standing is manifest it seems at first
glance one would think the order would
be different that it would be arising
then changing while standing and then
ceasing is there a reason why because
that that that order is is rooted in in
a completely mistaken wrong view of the
external point of view in regard to the
experience in regard to the fundamentals
of space and time so people assume the
external world which is independent of
me in my experience and that is external
world is also sort of possesses time in
which we are placed so to speak so time
kind of start extends for that external
assumption of yourself so you you think
that you have a reason you are enduring
and then you're ceasing
but that requires an external reference
point to see that kind of flow which is
actually impossible to see internally
because you can't step outside yourself
you can have that notion of a flow of a
flux in regard to external things around
vinegar in regard to objects of your
senses but you cannot have that kind of
reference point in regard to your own
senses so that's the that's why it can
only be described in seeing internally
phantom illogically which is how the
guerrilla struggle arising is manifested
or disappearing is manifested or
changing while standing is manifested
because if you look at the nature of a
rising it's like fading in which means
there is no first point
for which thing wasn't and then it is
like you call the moment where it
appeared that's impossible
they can only be done in an external
manner but when you're trying to apply
to your own situation and the sense is
the sense basis you cannot see it like
that so then if you look at it you see
that I read are already sorry then
either already fading in or either
fading out
doesn't matter which it is persisting
while changing or changing while
standing why because if you have
something fading in means it's
increasing in its presence means it's
staying the same thing while it's
increasing in its present and that's
just another way of saying it's changing
while remaining the same if something is
fading out as in its the intensifying in
its presence again it stays the same
thing you can still designate is the
same thing while it's changing as in its
fading out so whether it's arising or
changing you can say it's persisting
well what sort of well it's arising or
disappearing you can say that it's
persisting while changing just in a
different direction so that's why the
Buddha would describe arising is
manifest ceasing is manifested resisting
while training is manifest there are
three ways of looking at an arisen
present phenomenon either intensifying
to be intensifying which is either way
to see it as changing while remaining
the same
meditation instructions its idea things
are constantly changing dude
I've heard all kinds of ideas like every
fraction of a second measuring it in my
nanoseconds remember seconds of these
little moments of being here I guess of
watching changes to prove something yeah
it's quite unfortunate that sort of I
mean a fortune but not surprising did
that's helped me because it is the
external point of view of ourselves it's
like one of the fundamental wrong views
they can be manifested they can manifest
itself in different ways but presently
contemporarily the most common way is
the scientific outlook as in you see
yourself inhabiting this public world
that it's it's it's there before you and
is going to carry on after you but any
notions of the world that you can have
it's based on your experience as a whole
on your sense basis thus you having a
view that it's independent of that
because of which that view is there in
the first place that's why it's a wrong
view so as I as I said just just two
seconds ago any notion of flux requires
an on changing reference point so you
can see things are flowing against this
and you can do that in regard to your
sense objects but you cannot do that in
regard to your sense basis and sense
objects as in you cannot step outside of
the five aggregates and your situation
as a whole and then see it is it's
constantly changing or evil world you
measure the Nano fractions of it that's
unthinkable but you can come up with a
bit up with a pleasing theory and in a
very neat description of it that if but
they would require a person to inhabit
the wrong view of the external world in
regard to myself and then everything
will make sense but because it's rooted
in that misperception of yours of the
fundamental aspect of the situation he
cannot resolve in any knowledge
he writes shortly after these three
characteristics of the determined or
characteristics by where by what it
determined may be known as such it's
nicely indicate the fundamental
structure in virtue of which things are
big in virtue of which is to say things
are distinct one from another is also in
virtue of this structure all experience
including the are hunts is intentional
or Thalia logicals a thing they point to
other possible things
it's not exactly clear what is meant
when he's saying obviously we can say
this thing is the same things that you
can see that it's enduring at some level
but the idea that also there's three
characteristics are that by that guy
kind of that by which there are
intentions as soon as it gets as two
things at all how do we say that seeing
a thing enduring or fading in fading out
prefers to intentionality well it it's
based on it because changing while
remaining the same requires well
requires at least two different levels
of their generality requires a certain
sameness while within that so
simultaneously present to that same is
that thing is changing until the has
changed to such a degree that then
abruptly you just see now it's a
different thing present there as in your
experience has changed so that in itself
it's already intentional the the things
on the lower level of generality that's
where he talks about the fundamental
structure are bound by their general
determination of still being the same
thing when that changes to a greater
degree and that that determination
ceases and that's the that's the basis
of any intentionality that's the basis
of any choices you can make the
possibilities that are implied in the
given experience as a whole are within
that experience at all and in return
they actually determined that experience
as a whole for what you know or how you
know it